# Dr. Guglielmo Gemignani

Residence: Munich, Germany

Tel: +49 1525 7841084 / +39 328 5510100 Email: guglielmogemignani@gmail.com

## in (7) 🤄

#### **Brief Research Statement**

A highly experienced professional in the field of robotics and AI with over 10 years of experience programming robots and over 5 years of experience managing teams of engineers. Holds a PhD in Robotics and Artificial Intelligence and has strong technical and interpersonal skills. Has contributed to the field with over 20 academic publications and 2 patents, and has participated in European projects. Seeking the next step in their career as a manager in the robotics field.

## Skills

Management: 5+ years. Trained in Agile Development, Nonviolent Communication, and Effective Leadership

Programming: 10+ years. Experience primarily with Python, C++, and Prolog in ROS

Languages: Italian (native), English (fluent), German (B2), French (A2)

# **Employment Experiences**

#### MAGAZINO GMBH

## **Head of Robotic Integration** (03/2022 - Present)

Disciplinary supervisor and technical lead of a team of 10+ developers in charge of robot architecture design, robot behaviors development and product QA. Additionally, responsible for a commercial Behavior Tree based framework, adopted by multiple multinational companies to develop behaviors for their autonomous robots.

Keywords: VDA5050, Integrator CLI, SW & HW QA, Gazebo, GitLab, Docker, Podman, Behavior Trees.

#### Team Lead Behaviors & Reasoning (01/2018 - 03/2022)

Disciplinary supervisor and technical lead of a team in charge of robot behaviors development, data analysis, and SW QA. The team contributed to the development of three products: TORU, SOTO, ACROS.AI. *Keywords: Behavior trees, Automated planning, SW QA, Gazebo, Buildbot, Data Analysis, Pandas, Jupyter, GCP.* 

#### Senior Robotics Software Engineer (02/2017 - 01/2018)

Responsible for the behaviors, navigation and deployment of TORU.

The robot won several awards, such as Best ROS Based Product 2020, Best product LogiMAT 2018, etc. *Keywords: ROS, Behavior Trees, Django, Diagnostics, Prolog, Error modeling and Handling*.

# **Robotics Software Engineer** (11/2015 - 02/2017)

Robot navigation and behavior developer.

Keywords: ROS, Move Base, Topological graph planner, NetworkX, Django, Behavior Trees.

## **Additional Experiences**

## Open and Closed Source Contributions

#### Author/maintainer/contributor of various open and closed source projects

*Repositories*: ros/diagnostics, pyswip, behavior\_trees, robot\_state\_reasoning, topological\_graph\_planner, ros/geometry2, PetriNetPlans, etc.

#### Academic and Research Roles

## **European Project Reviewer**

Project Names: SciRoc (EU-H2020 funded project)

## SPC, PC and Reviewer for various international conferences

Conferences: IJCAI, ECAI, AI\*IA, etc.

## **International Research Project Contributor**

Project Names: AIPlan4EU (EU-H2020 funded project), RoboDevOps (Bavarian funded project)

## RoboCup 2013 Standard Platform League

## Team Leader and coordination and behaviors developer of the SPQR team

Achieved 1st place at Iran Open 2013 & 3rd place at German Open 2013

#### **Education**

## CARNEGIE MELLON UNIVERSITY

**PhD Visitor**: CORAL Laboratory under the supervision of Prof. Manuela Veloso *Visiting Period*: 09/2014 - 03/2015

# Sapienza - Università di Roma, Italy

## PhD in Robotics and Artificial Intelligence (11/2012 - 02/2016)

 ${\it Title~of~the~Thesis}: \ Acquiring \ Knowledge \ Through \ Multi-Modal \ Human-Robot \ Interaction$ 

Advisor: Prof. Daniele Nardi

## Laurea Magistrale in Electronic Physics (09/2010 - 10/2012)

Title of the Thesis: Study of the Readout System of a Microcapillary Position Detector Filled with Scintillating Liquid

Grade: 110/110 cum laude, excellence program

#### Università degli Studi di Pisa, Italy

## **Laurea Triennale in Physics** (09/2007 - 07/2010)

Title of the Thesis: Numerical Solution of the Unidimensional Scrödinger Equation

## **Publications**

#### JOURNALS, BOOK CHAPTERS, AND PATENTS

- Capabilities for error categorization, reporting and introspection of a technical apparatus. **G. Gemignani**, M. Grimm, M. Tenorth. European Patent and Trademark Office, filed on August 8th, 2021.
- Controlling an apparatus, e.g., a robot, with a behavior tree. **G. Gemignani**. European Patent and Trademark Office, filed on February 4th, 2021.
- *Dialogue with Robots to Support Symbiotic Autonomy*. A. Vanzo, D. Croce, E. Bastianelli, **G. Gemignani**, R. Basili, D. Nardi. Dialogues with Social Robots, pp. 331-342, 2017.
- Living with Robots: Interactive Environmental Knowledge Acquisition. G. Gemignani, R. Capobianco, E. Bastianelli, D. D. Bloisi, L. Iocchi, D. Nardi. Robotics and Autonomous Systems, RAS 2016.

#### **CONFERENCES**

- Planning for Automated Testing of Implicit Constraints in Behavior Trees. U. Köckemann, D. Calisi, **G. Gemignani**, J. Renoux, and A. Saffiotti. International Conference on Automated Planning and Scheduling, ICAPS 2023.
- Automatic Extraction of Structural Representations of Environments. R. Capobianco, **G. Gemignani**, D. D. Bloisi, D. Nardi, and L. Iocchi. Chapter in Intelligent Autonomous Systems 13, 2016.
- Multi-Robot Search for a Moving Target: Integrating World Modeling, Task Assignment and Context. F. Riccio, E. Borzi,G. Gemignani, and D. Nardi. International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems, IROS 2016.RoboCup Best Paper Award.
- *Multi-Robot Task Acquisition through Sparse Coordination*. S. Klee, **G. Gemignani**, M. Veloso, and D. Nardi. International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems, IROS 2015.
- Disambiguating Localization Symmetry through a Multi-Clustered Particle Filtering. F. Previtali, G. Gemignani, L. Iocchi and D. Nardi. International Conference on Multisensor Fusion and Information Integration 2015.
- *Graph-Based Task Libraries for Robots: Generalization and Autocompletion.* **G. Gemignani**, S. D. Klee, D. Nardi, and M. Veloso. AI\*IA 2015.
- Approaching Qualitative Spatial Reasoning About Distances and Directions in Robotics. **G. Gemignani**, R. Capobianco, and D. Nardi. AI\*IA 2015.
- Language-Based Sensing Descriptors for Robot Object Grounding. G. Gemignani, M. Veloso, and D. Nardi. RoboCup Symposium 2015. Best Paper Award.
- *Context-based Coordination for a Multi-Robot Soccer Team.* F. Riccio, E. Borzi, **G. Gemignani**, and D. Nardi. RoboCup Symposium 2015.
- On Task Recognition and Generalization in Long-Term Robot Teaching (Extended Abstract). G. Gemignani, S. Klee, M. Veloso, and D. Nardi. 14th International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems, AAMAS 2015.
- Teaching Robots Parametrized Executable Plans Through Spoken Interaction. **G. Gemignani**, E. Bastinaelli, and D. Nardi. 14th International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems, AAMAS 2015.

- Automatic Extraction of Structural Representations of Environments. R. Capobianco, G. Gemignani, D. Bloisi, D. Nardi, and L. Iocchi. 13th International Conference on Intelligent Autonomous Systems, IAS 2014.
- *On-line Semantic Mapping*. E. Bastianelli, D. Bloisi, R. Capobianco, F. Cossu, **G. Gemignani**, L. Iocchi, and D. Nardi. 16th International Conference on Advanced Robotics, ICAR 2013.

#### WORKSHOPS

- *Dialog with Robots to Support Symbiotic Autonomy*. D. Nardi, R. Basili, E. Bastianelli, D. Croce, **G. Gemignani**, A. Vanzo. In Proceedings of the 7th International Workshop on Spoken Dialog Systems, 2016.
- Contexts for Symbiotic Autonomy: Semantic Mapping, Task Teaching and Social Robotics. R. Capobianco, G. Gemignani, L. Iocchi, D. Nardi, F. Riccio, and A. Vanzo. In Proceedings of the AAAI'16 Workshop on Symbiotic Cognitive Systems, 2016.
- *Interactive Semantic Mapping: Experimental Evaluation.* **G. Gemignani**, D. Nardi, D. D. Bloisi, R. Capobianco, and L. Iocchi. Springer Tracts in Advanced Robotics, Experimental Robotics, 2016.
- Multi Robot Perception and Action: World Modeling and Task Allocation. F. Riccio, M. T. Lazáro, G. Gemignani, and D. Nardi. RSS 2015 Workshop Principle of multi-robot systems.
- *Task Recognition and Generalization in Long-Term Robot Teaching*. **G. Gemignani**, S. Klee, M. Veloso, and D. Nardi. Autonomous Robots and Multirobot Systems, ARMS 2015.
- *Symbiotic Semantic Mapping*. **G. Gemignani**, D. Nardi, D. D. Bloisi, R. Capobianco, and L. Iocchi. International Symposium on Experimental Robotics, ISER 2014.
- *Knowledge-Based Reasoning on Semantic Maps.* R. Capobianco, **G. Gemignani**, D. Nardi, D. Bloisi, and L. Iocchi. Knowledge Representation and Reasoning in Robotics Symposium at AAAI Spring Symposium, 2014.
- Knowledge Representation for Robots through Human-Robot Interaction. E. Bastianelli, D. Bloisi, R. Capobianco,
  G. Gemignani, L. Iocchi, and D. Nardi. Knowledge Representation and Reasoning in Robotics Workshop at 29<sup>th</sup> International Conference on Logic Programming, 2013.